# Daniel Borba Guimarães da Costa

## FullStack Web Developer

♥ Uberaba, MG - Brazil

**\ +55 34 99118-8815** 

☑ danielbgc02@gmail.com

github.com/DanielBGC in linkedin.com/in/danielbgc/

## **Summary**

I'm a full-stack web developer with over 2 years of experience in the field. I specialize in, NodeJS, OracleDB, Git, REST APIs, following the best practices of Clean Code. I have worked with both SCRUM and Kanban as agile methodologies. Additionally, I have knowledge in NextJS, React, React Native, MySQL, Prisma, Docker and other technologies.

I have a conversational level of English, and for me it is very easy to learn new technologies and I am always seeking new challenges in my career.

Currently, I am employed at Bravo Serviços Logísticos, working on the development of new features, conducting tests, and maintaining the 'Evolog' system. This system focuses on the logistics segment and provides real-time load monitoring. I have been able to quickly grow within the company, starting as an intern and reaching the analyst level in less than 1 year.

My primary objective is to work on projects that allow me to apply the knowledge I have gained in various technologies, while also contributing to the success and growth of the company. I am eager to acquire new experiences that contribute to my professional development.

## **Work Experience**

## FullStack Developer - Analyst

01/04/2022 - Currently

Bravo Serviços Logísticos

I am currently employed as a FullStack Developer, dedicated to enhancing and expanding the 'Evolog' module using technologies such as Angular, TypeScript, ES6+, Node.js, Git, Bootstrap, OracleDB, among others. In addition to my development responsibilities, I also serve a crucial role in ensuring the overall system security, proactively preventing potential hacker attacks.

I am responsible for implementing security measures, conducting vulnerability assessments, and applying best practices to safeguard the system against security threats. This includes staying updated with the latest security trends, conducting regular security audits, and implementing necessary security patches.

Furthermore, I have served as a project leader for promoting foreign language proficiency within the company, with a focus on English and Spanish. My role also involves conducting corrective and preventive maintenance on the system, identifying errors or failures, and providing technical support to users.

#### FullStack Developer - Junior Analyst

20/08/2021 - 31/03/2022

Bravo Serviços Logísticos

I worked as a FullStack Developer, focusing on improving and expanding the 'Evolog' module using Angular, TypeScript, ES6+, Node.js, Git, Bootstrap, and handling database administration and maintenance (OracleDB). In addition, I was responsible for identifying and fixing errors and failures through corrective and preventive maintenance on the systems.

#### Web Developer Intern

03/05/2021 - 20/08/2021

Bravo Serviços Logísticos

During my internship, I acquired skills in developing web applications utilizing Angular, TypeScript, Node.js, relational databases (OracleDB), Git, Bootstrap, and other related technologies.

#### **Administrative Assistant**

04/11/2020 - 30/04/2021

Dtc Servicos Odontologicos LTDA (Max Human)

I worked as an Administrative Assistant in a dental clinic, where I was responsible for a wide range of activities. These included financial control in the accounts department, telemarketing and collection calls, developing strategies to expand the business, prospecting new customers, reactivating inactive customers, handling internal and external sales, and managing invoices.

#### **Eletronics Technician**

05/03/2018 - 19/06/2018

SAK'S Comércio e Confecções Eireli

I worked as an apprentice, where I had my initial exposure to programming, specifically using the C language for technical education in Electronics at SENAI.

#### **Education**

#### **Bachelor's degree in Analysis and Systems Development (Technology)**

February, 2020 - December, 2022

IFTM (Instituto Federal do Triângulo Mineiro)

#### **Technical degree in Eletronics**

February, 2017 - September, 2018

SENAI (Serviço Nacional de Aprendizagem Industrial)

I have experience in the development, repair, and installation of electronic components and devices. I have also performed corrective maintenance and implemented preventive measures in various fields such as civil construction, electronics, information technology, telecommunications, and more.

#### **Fluency in English**

February, 2015 - August, 2019

CIEL (Centro Interescolar Estadual de Línguas)

#### **Portfolio**

Project	Description	Technologies Used
https://github.com/DanielBGC/ <u>next-auth-jwt</u>	A Next.js application that simulates an authentication system using JSON Web Tokens (JWT).	NextJS, React, Context API, TypeScript, Tailwindcss, Axios Nookies
https://github.com/DanielBGC/ <u>mvp-next-prisma</u>	An application that showcases the efficient and rapid creation of Minimum Viable Products (MVPs) using the Next.js + Prisma stack.	NextJS, Next-Auth, React, TypeScript, Tailwindcss, Docker, Prisma, PostgreSQL e MySQL
https://github.com/DanielBGC/nextjs-firebase-crud	NextJS Application Connected to Firebase to create a CRUD.	NextJS, React, TypeScript, Tailwindcss, Firebase e Firestore
https://github.com/DanielBGC/ <u>node-deploy</u>	NodeJS application using fastify, prism and zod with hosting on render.com platform.	NodeJS, Fastify, Zod, TypeScript, Docker, Prisma e PostgreSQL
https://github.com/DanielBGC/ <u>prisma-starter</u>	Creation of an initial NodeJS API, exploring the concepts of the fastify framework and the prism ORM.	NodeJS, Fastify, Zod, Typescript, Docker, Prisma e PostgreSQL
https://github.com/DanielBGC/ <u>micro-interactions-app</u>	A mobile application developed using React Native, focusing on exploring microinteractions to enhance the user's interaction with the interface.	React Native, Expo, Typescript, GestureHandler e Reanimated
https://github.com/DanielBGC/ <u>progress-read-app</u>	A mobile application that incorporates the concept of screen scrolling to showcase the progress of reading a page.	React Native, Expo, Typescript, Reanimated

#### **Events & Certificates**

#### Hackaton CCR (Shawee)

I participated in a hackathon focused on generating ideas to improve the daily routine of truck drivers, with a specific focus on enhancing their physical and mental well-being. Our project aimed to address this challenge by developing an application that maps the main difficulties experienced by truck drivers. The application enables truck drivers to provide immediate feedback about their trips and stops, allowing for long-term problem-solving and support. This solution aims to improve the overall quality of life for truck drivers on the road.

The Complete Oracle SQL Certification Course	<u>Certificate here</u>
ORM with NodeJS: API with Sequelize and MySQL	- <u>Certificate here</u>
SQL Queries in Oracle: projections, selecions, joins and views	Certificate here
NodeJS: Creating your library	- <u>Certificate here</u>
NodeJS: REST API with Express and MongoDB	- <u>Certificate here</u>
HTTP: Understanding the Web	- <u>Certificate here</u>
Stress Management: Optmize your leadership	Certificate here
Strategic Communication in Leadership: How to engage and influence people	- <u>Certificate here</u>